<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Hacking Articles</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Hacking Articles</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:00:30 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://havocsec.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Hidden Risk in Modern Tech: Why Centralizing Everything in One Provider Is a Security Calamity Waiting to Happen</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/the-hidden-risk-in-modern-tech-why-centralizing-everything-in-one-provider-is-a-security-calamity-waiting-to-happen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/the-hidden-risk-in-modern-tech-why-centralizing-everything-in-one-provider-is-a-security-calamity-waiting-to-happen/</guid><description>Modern infrastructure looks powerful, but it’s increasingly fragile. When companies centralize everything under a single provider, a single outage can cascade across entire ecosystems — from authentication failures to global service blackouts. Using major AWS, Azure, and Cloudflare outages as evidence, this post breaks down why centralization is a hidden architectural risk and explains how to design systems that remain resilient even when your cloud provider collapses.</description></item><item><title>How I Levelled Up My Pentesting Workflow by Automating the Boring Stuff</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/how-i-levelled-up-my-pentesting-workflow-by-automating-the-boring-stuff/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/how-i-levelled-up-my-pentesting-workflow-by-automating-the-boring-stuff/</guid><description>Most pentesters hit a ceiling without realizing it - too much manual recon, too many repeated steps, and too little time spent actually exploiting. I break down how I automated my workflow, removed friction, and built a system that lets me operate faster, smarter, and with fewer mistakes — in real engagements and CTFs.</description></item><item><title>The Good Side of Open Source: Why It Matters to You</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post11/</guid><description>Open source software is more than just a coding philosophy; it&amp;rsquo;s a movement that empowers individuals and fosters innovation. Discover how it impacts your life and the tech you use every day.</description></item><item><title>Level Up Your Learning: How to Master Anything (Even if You're Starting from Scratch!)</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post10/</guid><description>In a world where knowledge is power, learning how to learn is your ultimate superpower. This guide will take you through the essential steps to become a self-taught expert in any field.</description></item><item><title> The Dark Side of Open Source: When Community Projects Go Rogue</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post9/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post9/</guid><description>Open source software is built by communities and shared freely, but it can also have its dark side. This article explores the risks of malicious code, abandoned projects, and supply chain attacks, while offering tips on how to stay safe in the open-source world.</description></item><item><title>My thoughts on being an Hacker</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post8/</guid><description>MY THOUGHTS ON BEING A HACKER A hacker is someone who understands how the world works. It&amp;rsquo;s about knowing what happens when you type &amp;ldquo;google.com&amp;rdquo; and press Enter. It&amp;rsquo;s about knowing how your computer turns on, about memory training, A20, all of that. It&amp;rsquo;s about modern processors, their caches, and their side channels. It&amp;rsquo;s about DSi bootloaders and how the right electromagnetic faults can be used to jailbreak them. And it&amp;rsquo;s about how Spotify and Widevine and AES and SGX work so you can free your music from the shackles of DRM.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ Top 10 Real-World Exploits That Started as CTF Challenges</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post7/</guid><description>Introduction Capture The Flag (CTF) competitions are a cornerstone of cybersecurity education and skill development. These challenges, ranging from intricate reverse engineering puzzles to complex web exploitation scenarios, push participants to think like attackers and defenders in a controlled environment. While often seen as purely academic exercises, the techniques and vulnerabilities explored in CTFs frequently mirror, and sometimes even directly lead to, the discovery and exploitation of real-world security flaws.</description></item><item><title>Hacking: Beyond the Hollywood Stereotype</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post6/</guid><description>You’ve seen it in movies—dark room, black hoodie, green text flashing on the screen, and suddenly, &amp;ldquo;I’m in.&amp;quot; But hold on! That’s not real hacking. Sure, you could sit in the dark, wear a hoodie, and stare at a terminal until your eyes hurt (and your mom yells at you—trust me, mine did). But hacking is so much more than that.
So, what is hacking?
At its core, hacking is about finding vulnerabilities in systems and exploiting them to gain access, information, or control.</description></item><item><title>Proxying Like a Pro</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post5/</guid><description>&lt;em>Proxies are indispensable tools for managing, monitoring, and securing network traffic while maintaining anonymity or bypassing restrictions. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a developer debugging applications, a penetration tester evading detection, or a forensics investigator tracing malicious activity, mastering proxies is a game-changer. This blog post dives deep into proxying, covering proxy fundamentals, practical setups with tools like Squid, Charles, Nginx, and ProxyChains, and advanced techniques for pivoting and evading detection. Let&amp;rsquo;s proxy like a pro!&lt;/em>.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking The Kernel superpowers</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post4/</guid><description>&lt;em>The Linux kernel, the heart of countless operating systems and devices&lt;/em>.</description></item><item><title>Building Your Own Ethical Hacking Lab Using Linux: A Complete Guide</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post3/</guid><description>This guide walks you through setting up a complete ethical hacking lab using Linux. Learn how to install the right tools, deploy vulnerable machines, configure secure virtual networks, and build a safe space to develop practical cybersecurity skills—perfect for OSCP prep, penetration testing practice, or hands-on learning.</description></item><item><title>Cracking the Code: The Ultimate CTF Companion</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post2/</guid><description>Dive into the world of Capture The Flag competitions—from solving basic cryptography and web challenges to mastering reverse engineering and forensics. Follow hands-on examples, terminal walkthroughs, and expert tips to become a competitive CTF player.</description></item><item><title>Mastering Bash Scripting: From Zero to Automation Hero</title><link>https://havocsec.me/blog/post1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://havocsec.me/blog/post1/</guid><description>Learn Bash scripting from fundamentals to advanced automation with real-world examples, terminal outputs, and pro tips for security and efficiency.</description></item></channel></rss>